NIKHIL JAISWAL

Technology Analyst
Email: nikhilsrkian@gmail.com
Phone: +91-9801320829

Location: Bangalore, Karnataka, India LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/nikhil-jaiswal-a162721a7

SUMMARY

Technology Analyst with over 3 years and 7 month of experience as .NET Developer, with a strong focus on optimizing Continuous Integration/Continuous Deployment processes, improving application performance, and delivering innovative solutions. Actively seeking opportunities to contribute to organizational success while advancing my professional growth.

WORK EXPERIENCE

TECHNOLOGY ANALYST, INFOSYS

Jul 2024 - Present

Project: The Open University Responsibilities:

• Experienced in Agile practices, code reviews, peer testing, and mentoring to foster team growth. Focused on hands-on coding, efficient production deployments, and post-deployment monitoring.

Tech Stack: C#, ASP.NET (MVC, Web Forms), Azure DevOps (CI/CD),MsSql,WebAPIs,SOAP,REST, Javascript

SENIOR SYSTEM ENGINEER, INFOSYS

Jul 2021 - Jun 2024

Project: The Open University Responsibilities:

- Managed CI/CD processes with Azure DevOps, deploying over 40 code changes monthly.
- Developed and maintained applications using MVC and ASP.NET Web Forms, implementing best practices that enhanced team productivity by 20%.
- Collaborated with analysts and clients to clarify requirements, which improved project efficiency by 20% and client satisfaction by 15%.
- Monitored registrations and implemented banner messages, which increased user engagement by 15% and reducing registration errors by 10%.

Tech Stack: C#, ASP.NET (MVC, Web Forms), Azure DevOps (CI/CD) Project Details:

- The Open University: A leading public distance learning and research university in the UK, serving a global community of undergraduate and postgraduate students.
 - Student Home: Improved user experience for the student registration and qualification management platform.
 - Module Chooser: Improved the module selection and management system, increasing student satisfaction.
 - OTIS1BD: Developed features for detailed future study options, streamlining the registration process.
 - Product Description: Enhanced the application to offer detailed information on academic products and services.
 - Qual Reg: Improved the registration system for qualifications and academic credentials, increasing efficiency.

Intern, Infosys Feb 2021 - May 2021

Project: Routemap Application Responsibilities:

• Developed the Routemap application for route planning, which improved navigation efficiency by 25% and reduced travel time by 15%.

Tech Stack: .NET, HTML, CSS, MySQL

SKILLS

• Database: SQL

• Frontend: HTML, CSS

Frameworks: ASP.NET, MVC, Web API
Tools: Azure DevOps, Visual Studio

• Soft Skills: Strategic Thinking, Communication

RECOGNITION

Certificate of Appreciation

View Certificate

EDUCATION

B.Tech in Computer Science, Galgotias University

Percentage: 83.8%

Senior Secondary Education in PCM, R.R College

Percentage: 64.2%

Jul 2017 - Jul 2021

Jul 2014 - Jul 2017